Preliminary Guide to the Ralph Clement Bryant Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ralph Clement Bryant papers
1897-1939
MS 877
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
(11 boxes)
Photographs, negatives, and postcards showing logging and lumbering operations in the United States, Hawaii, Japan, the Philippines, Sweden and Switzerland.
Bryant, Ralph Clement, 1877-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Yale University Forest History Department, 1969.
Scope and Contents
The Ralph C. Bryant Papers consist mainly of photographs, negatives, and postcards that show lumbering operations and related subjects. They are arranged in four sections: 1) mounted photographs; 2) unmounted photographs and negatives; 3) postcards; and 4) unsorted negatives. The mounted photographs are grouped by location and by type of timber, as they came from the donor. The unmounted photographs and negatives and the postcards are arranged alphabetically under headings copied or paraphrased from the original wrappers. The unsorted negatives are bundled in their original envelopes, most of which are labeled.
The papers also contain three apparent lists of photographs, two of which are labeled as lists of films. Some or all of the listed items may be included in the Bryant Papers, but there is no apparent relation between the organization of the lists and the organization of the mounted photographs.
The Ralph C. Bryant Papers were transferred to the Department of Manuscripts and Archives from the Department of Forest History in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Ralph C. Bryant (1877-1939): forester of New York State Forest, Fish and Game Commission, 1900-1901; assistant chief forester of Philippine Bureau of Forestry, 1902-1905; U.S. Forestry Service, 1905-1906; professor of lumbering, Yale University, 1906-1939.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Conservation of natural resources; Environmental protection; Forests and forestry; Logging -- United States; Lumbering -- United States; Sawmills -- United States; Postcards; Educators; Foresters; Bryant, Ralph Clement, 1877-; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Forestry
- Inventory, 1899-1939; 4 linear feet (11 boxes)
  - Lists
    - "List of films sent to W. C. Ives, Mystic, Conn., January 8, 1912" (Box 1)
    - "R. C. Bryant films, Cal. trip", undated (Box 1)
    - List of [photographs?], undated (Box 1)
  - Mounted photographs
    - Hawaii, undated (Box 1)
    - Japan, undated (Box 1)
    - Philippines, undated (Box 1)
    - Switzerland, undated (Box 1)
    - U.S.A.
      - Cornell Camp, 1917 (Box 1)
      - Mfg.
        - Connecticut, 1913-1914 (Box 1)
        - Hoists, undated (Box 1)
        - Log and lumber, handling Douglas fir, 1913-1914 (Box 1)
        - Sawmills
          - Douglas fir, undated (Box 2)
          - North, 1922, undated (Box 2)
          - Redwood, 1900-1925 (Box 2)
          - Southern hardwood, 1900-1907 (Box 2)
          - Southern pine, 1907-1920 (Box 2)
          - Southern pine, 1907-1920 (Box 3)
          - Western pine, 1918, n.d (Box 3)
        - Seasoning
          - North, 1917 (Box 3)
          - Redwood, 1920-1925 (Box 3)
          - Southern pine, 1907-1917 (Box 3)
      - W & L
        - Appalachian, 1900-1910 (Box 3)
        - British Columbia, 1924, undated (Box 3)
        - Connecticut, 1914 (Box 3)
        - Cypress, 1907-1920 (Box 3)
        - Dams, 1899-1920 (Box 4)
        - Douglas fir, 1900-1939 (Box 4)
        - Flumes, 1909-1926 (Box 4)
        - Naval stores, 1908-1909 (Box 4)
        - North, 1897-1924 (Box 4)
        - North, 1897-1924 (Box 5)
        - Redwood, 1900-1939 (Box 5)
        - Southern hardwood, undated (Box 5)
        - Southern pine, 1907-1917 (Box 6)
        - Western pine, 1909-1939 (Box 6–7)
  - Unmounted photographs
    - California white pine, undated (Box 7)
    - Finland, undated (Box 7)
    - Logging, undated (Box 7)
    - Textbook illustrations, undated (Box 7)
  - Unmounted photographs and negatives
    - Anglo-American pulp and paper operation, 1930 (Box 8)
    - Apache Lumber Co. Mill, 1918 (Box 8)
    - Bryant, Ralph C., 1929 (Box 8)
    - Bryant (Arthur) & Son, Nurserymen, [c. 1905] (Box 8)
    - Cornell field trip to Stony Creek Mountain, 1899 (Box 8)
    - Cornell, 1917 (Box 8)
    - Cornell students on return from Mount Marcy, 1929 (Box 8)
    - Cornell forestry camp, undated (Box 8)
    - Crossett, Ark., 1919 (Box 8)
    - Crossett, Ark, [post-1925] (Box 8)
    - Crossett, Ark., 1926 (Box 8)
    - Crossett, Ark. (portable sawmill), 1927 (Box 8)
    - Crossett Western Lumber Co., 1916 (Box 8)
    - Germany (pulpwood logging), 1937 (Box 8)
    - Logging, undated (Box 8)
    - Logging, undated (Box 8)
    - Lumber, undated (Box 9)
    - Michigan, undated (Box 9)
    - Middlebury, Vt., 1931 August 1-2 (Box 9)
    - Storrs, Conn.
      - Portable sawmill, 1926 (Box 9)
      - Sawmill demonstration, 1926 (Box 9)
      - DeForest & Hotchkiss Co., 1926 (Box 9)
    - Superior National Forest (Weyerhauser Log Co.), 1929-1930 (Box 9)
    - [Textbook illustrations?], undated (Box 9)
    - Tropics, undated (Box 9)
    - Turpentine, undated (Box 9)
    - Urania, 1917 (Box 9)
    - Urania, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Urania sawmill, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Urania, undated (Box 9)
    - Wilmar, Ark., 1937-1938 (Box 9)
    - Y.F.S. camp (Vredenburgh, Ala.), 1916 (Box 9)
  - Postcards
    - Bogalusa, Louisiana, undated (Box 10)
    - Central Planing Mills (Vancouver, Wash.), undated (Box 10)
    - European forestry, undated (Box 10)
    - Germany, undated (Box 10)
    - Japan, undated (Box 10)
    - McCloud River (Cal.) Lumber Co., undated (Box 10)
    - Mengel (C.C.) & Bro., mahogany (Africa, Honduras, Kentucky), undated (Box 10)
    - Potlatch Lumber Co., 1913 (Box 10)
    - Priest River Experiment Station (Idaho), 1913 (Box 10)
    - Western logging, 1909-1934, undated (Box 10)
  - Unsorted negatives, 1911-1926 (Box 11)